Guide to the Richard Pollay Acme Advertising Collection, 1850s-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Series 14: Books and Monographs, 1880-1996 and undated
  - 100-14-025. Acme Steel Company. Know Your Company booklets, 1938 (Box 25)
    Two copies of Know our company and your job from Acme Steel Company, Riverdale Works, Chicago. One comes with a folded mimeographed form letter to each employee, dated July 18, 1938. One of the copies has Walter Wilkens handwritten and stamped on the cover.
  - 100-14-026. Acme Steel Company. Safety first booklet, undated (Box 25)
    Acme Steel Company. (Riverdale Works, Chicago) Safety first booklet. Brown cover, 11 pp. Good condition.
  - 100-14-027. Acme Steel Company. General Plant Safety Rules booklet, undated (Box 25)
    Acme Steel Company. (Riverdale Works, Chicago) booklet on general plant safety rules. Green cover, with Walter W Wilkens handwritten on pencil on front. 16 pp. Good condition.
  - 100-14-028. Acme Steel Company. Goodfellowship Club By-Laws booklets, 1943 (Box 25)
    Three copies of the Acme Steel Company (Riverdale Works, Chicago) Goodfellowship Club's By-Laws booklet. The Club is the workers association meant to provide funds for sick or disabled workers. Each booklet, 8 pp. All copies signed by worker Walter Wilkins.
  - 100-14-029. Acme Steel Company. Agreement between Acme Steel Company and Local Union #1053, 1941-1952 (Box 25)
    Three editions of the Agreement between the Acme Steel Company. (Riverdale Plant) and the United Steel Workers Local Union No. 1053 (also known as Steel Workers Organizing Committee in 1941). Booklets are the Agreements in 1941, 1943 and 1952. All owned by W. W. Wilkins. 1941 booklet has two inserts: postcard to Wilkins to attend union meeting and a paper slip with handwritten bonus calculations. All booklets in good condition.
  - 100-14-030. Acme Steel Company. Employees Representation Plan, 1930s (Box 25)
    Employees' Representation Plan booklet from the employees of the Acme Steel Company (Riverdale Works, Chicago). Gray cover, 12 pp. Some handwriting on the back cover. Property of Walter Wilkins.
  - 100-14-031. Acme Steel Company. Vacation Plan for Hourly Paid Employees booklet, 1937 (Box 25)
    Vacation Plan for Hourly Paid Employees booklet for workers at the Acme Steel Company. (Riverdale Works, Chicago). Orange cover, 8 pp. Good condition.
  - 100-14-032. American Iron and Steel Institute. Men Who Make Steel booklet, 1936 (Box 25)
    Publication of the American Iron and Steel Institute to show the principle and practice of collective cooperation. Illustrated, 51 pp. Red and orange cover. Some smudges on back cover.
  - 100-14-033. Acme Steel Company. Purchase Plan for Savings Bonds, 1942 (Box 25)
    War-time booklet entitled For defense: Employees voluntary purchase plan for United States savings bonds from Acme Steel Company. Booklet outlines how purchase plan works. Cover features pictures of B-16s and warships. Comes with folded insert from Local 1053 Victory our goal which invites workers cooperation for the purchase of US Savings bonds.
  - 100-14-034. Acme Code Company. Acme Commodity and Phrase Code, 1923 (Box 25)
    Acme code book compiled by A. C. Meisenbach; copyright by Acme Code Company; 15th printing in 1946. Handwritten codes in ink on pages 853 a-d. Inserted in book are three sheet of onion skinned paper with typewritten codes. Donation from UBC Rare Books and Special Collections, March 2005. Letter of donation attached.
  - 100-14-035. Acme Code Company. Acme Supplement, 1932 (Box 25)
    Acme Supplement, an addenda to the Acme Commodity and Phrase Code; covers a modern list of banks, vessels, cities, etc. See 100-14-34. Donation from UBC Rare Books and Special Collections, March 2005.
  - 100-14-036. Acme Bookbinding. Bindery Preparation Manual, 1989 (Box 25)
    Hard cover book. Blue fabric cover with gold lettering. 74 pages.
  - 100-14-037. Health Knowledge Inc. Acme French Fun No. 3 pin-up booklet, 1967 (Box 25)
    Paper booklet. Acme French Fun--Pin-Ups! Cartoons Laffs--Get Your Giggles the French Way!! Published by Health Knowledge Inc. Chip on front cover. Dry, brittle paper.
  - 100-14-038. Health Knowledge Inc. Acme Girlie Fun No. 11 pin-up booklet, 1968 (Box 25)
    Paper booklet. Acme Girlie Fun--Jokes--Cartoons--Lusty Action Poses!! Published by Health Knowledge Inc. Chips on front and back cover. Dry, Brittle paper.
  - 100-14-039. Acme Brick. Colossus In Clay: Acme Brick Company History, 1998 (Box 25)
    Hardcover book. History of Acme Brick Company. By Edwin E. Lehr. 288 pages. With dust jacket. Published for Acme Brick centennial 1998. Published by vanity press.
- Series 15: Specialty Aids, 1880s-2000 and undated
  - 100-15-001. Acme Lumber Company. Calendar/Blotter, 1959 (Box 42)
    Image of two monkeys in Christmas scene. Left side displays company information and calendar. Good condition.
  - 100-15-002. L. D. Berger Acme Ventilator Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Revolves around with the wind. No back draft. Helps make better chimney drafts. Image of product. Black-and-white text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-15-003. Acme Monroe Tag Company. Blotter, 1942? (Box 42)
    Army. Navy. How to Identify Them. Enlisted Men's Signia of Grade. Color images and text. Some yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-004. Clemence Bros. and Company. Postcard featuring Lillian Grub, undated (Box 42)
    Front: Sepia picture of woman identified as L. Grub. Reverse: Advertising for Acme Folding Bed. Card stained and signs of glue on reverse. Good condition.
  - 100-15-005. Acme Neon Accessory Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Order now--No Priority. Black-and-white images and text. Stained, small tears, and rust marks. Used-- ink on reverse. Water damage. Fair condition.
  - 100-15-006. Acme Neon Accessory Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Now Available!!! Copper Wire, Sheet Metal Screws Stained, small tears, and pencil marks. Used-- ink on reverse. Water damage. Fair condition.
  - 100-15-007. Acme Chair Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    We Rent Chairs, Card, and Banquet Tables. Black-and-white image. Black and Green text. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-008. Acme Publishing Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    This day you no doubt need some printing, good printing, the kind we do. July calendar top left--no year. White (faded) print against black background. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-009. Acme Blue Print Paper Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Drawing Materials. The Blue Prince draws your attention to the fact that after many years of careful specialization in the handling of drawing materials. Color image and text. Used. Good condition.
  - 100-15-010. Acme Corp. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    In Mexico Manana Means Tomorrow. In America Today Means Right Now! Black and red text and images. Used. Good condition.
  - 100-15-011. Acme Distributing Company. Blotter, 1949? (Box 42)
    Believe It or Not! Yewell, be glad you bought a UNIFLOW. Color. Used. Small tear along top. Good condition.
  - 100-15-012. Acme Printing Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Only plant in the country equipped to handle all classes of work. Red and black text. Good condition.
  - 100-15-013. Acme Flour Mills. Blotter, 1946 (Box 42)
    Better Milling is Our Business--Greater Profits is Our Aim. Top half: image of young woman in graduation robes: I am in a class by myself. Color. One bad crease has damaged item. Unused. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-014. Acme Flour Mills. Blotter, 1946 (Box 42)
    Better Milling is Our Business--Greater Profits is Our Aim. Top half: image of young woman in nurses uniform: they said I was to cute for wards. Color. Ink marks. Used. Good condition.
  - 100-15-015. Acme Silk Dyeing Corporation. Blotter, 1927 (Box 42)
    Acme Service includes 24 hour deliveries, guaranteed winding and matches, free fire and theft insurance. April calendar. Color. Illustration to left of clothed bear. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-016. Acme Silk Dyeing Corporation. Blotter, 1927 (Box 42)
    Acme Service includes 24 hour deliveries, guaranteed winding and matches, free fire and theft insurance. August calendar. Color. Illustration to left of clothed rabbits. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-017. Acme Silk Dyeing Corporation. Blotter, 1928 (Box 42)
    Acme Service includes 24 hour deliveries, guaranteed winding and matches, free fire and theft insurance. January calendar. Color. Illustration to left of horse. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-018. Acme Silk Dyeing Corporation. Blotter, 1927 (Box 42)
    Acme Service includes 24 hour deliveries, guaranteed winding and matches, free fire and theft insurance. July calendar. Color. Illustration to left of bees. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-019. Acme Carbon and Ribbon. Blotter, 1938? (Box 42)
    Curl controlled carbons (an exclusive Acme feature). Illustrates America's Loveliest Models. Ida Vollmar. Color. Used. Good condition.
  - 100-15-020. Acme Carbon and Ribbon. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    There's no trick to taking it easy. Do as many others are doing. Turn your Carbon Paper and Typewrite Ribbon problems over to us. Image of young woman on towel in summer clothing. Southern Exposure. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-021. Acme Carbon and Ribbon. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    If your resting a fence is a good place. But in business being on the fence is no fun Acme Clean Writing Cotton Ribbons. Image of young woman on fence. Howdy Friend! Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-022. Acme Carbon and Ribbon. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Easy to Take. Combined quality and economy that are easy on the pocket book-prompt service that is easy on the nerves Acme Silk Typewriter Ribbons. Image of young woman on corner of couch. A Corner on Beauty. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-023. Acme Carbon and Ribbon. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Rolling Along. If our popularity is any indication, folks do sure appreciate sweet service. Image of young woman leaning on bike. Beauty on Wheels. Name Genevieve rubbed out on lower bottom. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-024. Gaetjens, Berger and Wirth Inc. Blotter, 1939 (Box 42)
    Text is partially masked by ink stains. Image of 2 Scottish terriers. December calendar. Used. Creased and damaged. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-025. Acme Parts and Supply Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    When its bearings Four out of Five think TIMKIN first. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-026. Acme Chemical and Supplies Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Safe Rooting Assured With Oil-Dri Absorbents. Color. Some marking and scratches. Good condition.
  - 100-15-027. Acme Courts and Apartments. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Acme Courts and Apartments location and contact information. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-028. Acme Motor Court. Postcard, 1948 (Box 42)
    Acme Motor Court location and contact information. Color. Used. Good condition.
  - 100-15-029. Acme Oil Co's Super Service Station. Postcard, 1931 (Box 42)
    Color image of service station. Reverse: addressed and franked. Good condition.
  - 100-15-030. Acme Safeway Van and Storage. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Image of company van. Color. Reverse blank. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-031. Acme Cleansing Company. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Does your home express the charm of cleanliness? Color. Image of lounge and fireplace. Unused. Good condition. Reverse: company and product information.
  - 100-15-032. Acme Floor Company. Postcard, 1951 (Box 42)
    These floor layers have had over 90 years total work, same shop, same location, many same customers. Sepia photograph. Used. Addressed and franked. Good condition.
  - 100-15-033. National-Acme Manufacturing Company. Postcard, 1913 (Box 42)
    Postcard affirming order for screws. Dated and signed. Product image. Typed and hand written. Good condition.
  - 100-15-034. Acme. Centennial First Day cover, 1987 (Box 42)
    US Post Office, Acme Washington 98220, 1887-1987, Acme Hymnal, JoAnn Derus PM-1987, Named for the Acme Hymnal. Stamped, franked. Unaddressed. Mint condition.
  - 100-15-035. National-Acme Company. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Color image of factory and location. Addressed and franked. Date illegible. Written in pencil. Good condition.
  - 100-15-036. Acme Machine Company. Postcard, 1942 (Box 42)
    The Hospital, Acme Machine Company, and Public Library from the Winnipesauke River, Franklin, N. H. Black-and-white image. Dated and franked. Message in ink. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-037. Acme Cement Works. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Black-and-white image of factory, address. Unused. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-038. Unknown. Happy Birthday Postcard, 1913 (Box 42)
    Black-and-white image and text. Poem. Reverse: pencil text. Addressed to Acme Fireless Cooker Company requesting free manual and cookbook. Yellowing, stained. Water damage. Good condition.
  - 100-15-039. Meyercord Co. Window sign, undated (Box 42)
    Color sign Acme For Amplification. Reverse has instruction on how to affix to window. Company information and product number. Some stains. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-040. Acme postcard, 1914 (Box 42)
    Pack your grip and come to Acme. You'll never regret it. Color. Addressed, stamped and franked. Writing in ink. Minor marking. Good condition.
  - 100-15-041. New Acme Hotel. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Image of hotel room. Color. Unused. In pencil: #44 $1.50. Good condition. Reverse: Hot and cold water and telephone in every room. Free shower. Rooms $1.50 and up. Every room alike. Finest Hotel in Billings.
  - 100-15-042. Harris Photo Card Company. Acme Pittston Laundry. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Black-and-white image of horses pulling decorated wagon. Unused. Circa 1900s. Good condition. Reverse: Harris Photo Card Company. Pittston Penn. and N.Y. City.
  - 100-15-043. Acme Wire Company. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Image of tram and horse and buggy. Color. Unused. Creased and shows signs of wear. Circa 1900s. Fair condition.
  - 100-15-044. Acme Court. Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Aerial view of Acme Court on US 67 70--2 1/2 miles SW of Little Rock Ark. Color. Image of court units and insert of room. Unused. Writing in ink. Pencil: $4.00. Good condition. Reverse: information on rates and location. $3.00 for 2 people, 5.00 and 6.00 for 4 people.
  - 100-15-045. Acme Business College. Postcard, 1942 (Box 42)
    Black-and-white photograph of male and female graduates from Acme Business College. Addressed, stamped and franked. Good condition. Reverse: This group of Acme Graduates will earn more than $25,000.00 this year. They are happy because they are financially independent. You can be as well when you complete one of our courses. Why not get a free catalog?
  - 100-15-046. Acme Cabinet Company. Card, undated (Box 42)
    Pink and white card Acme Cabinet Company. Address included. Bookcases. Ornate lettering and decoration. Some marking. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-047. Acme Washing Machine Company. Card, undated (Box 42)
    The Acme Washer Has No Equal. Black-and-white text and image. Yellowing. Small hole. Good condition. Reverse: No boiling! No rubbing! Sold on its merits! It saves time and soap! Washes finest fabrics without injury! Saves double its cost in non-wear and tear of clothes! Included price and agents name.
  - 100-15-048. Acme Restaurant. Card, undated (Box 42)
    View showing part of the Acme Restaurant. Black-and-white. Patrons shown in restaurant. Good condition. Reverse: Restaurant location and information. White help employed in all departments.
  - 100-15-049. Acme Camera Exchange. Card, undated (Box 42)
    Black-and-white image. Man in canoe. Company location and information on reverse. Good condition.
  - 100-15-050. Acme Air Travel. Coaster, undated (Box 42)
    Red, white and blue images and text. Fares, company address and contact information. Images of aeroplanes follow the edges. Good condition.
  - 100-15-051. Acme Skateboard Logo, 1980? (Box 42)
    White land blue logo, unused. Blue backing attached. Good condition.
  - 100-15-052. Emotional Rescue. Birthday card, undated (Box 42)
    Practical Birthday card. How do you compare with other men? Novelty card. Inside reads: The Acme Patent Dick Gauge! Instructions: Insert willy to find appropriate sized hole No writing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-053. Kerston Bros. Company. Birthday Card, undated (Box 42)
    Image of witch in Acme Food grocery store with basket of pumpkins. Color. Text written in pen inside card. Yellowing at edges. Good condition.
  - 100-15-054. Ink group. Birthday card, undated (Box 42)
    Thin card board. Red, Black, and White text and image in style of a cassette tape. Inside: I love to hear the sound of your voice! Good condition.
  - 100-15-055. Christmas card, undated (Box 42)
    Image of Father Christmas stuck in chimney--Acme alarm ringing. Card has been cut out of original. Color. Good condition.
  - 100-15-056. Canada Post. Direct mail advertising booklet, undated (Box 42)
    Cold calls, hot prospects and other salesman stories. Image in booklet of Acme salesman. Color cover. Black-and-white pages and text. Good condition.
  - 100-15-057. Acme Bar and Grill. Table napkin, undated (Box 42)
    Acme Bar and Grill. Good condition.
  - 100-15-058. Acme Lumber and Manufacturing Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Decorative image and text I remember the house where I was born. Company information and location. Blotter unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-059. Acme. Writing tablet, undated (Box 42)
    Color image of young boy and teacher. Scholars Delight. Back attached, no pages between. Front page has some staining and yellowing. Back page is creased, stained and marked. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-060. Philip Morris Inc. Manufacturers coupon, 2000 (Box 42)
    Merit Ultima cigarette coupon, Acme name on coupon, likely the grocery store. Folded and ripped on one edge. Fair condition.
  - 100-15-061. Acme Novelty. One Buck, undated (Box 42)
    Phony Mazuma One Buck. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-15-062. Acme Plumbing Supply Company. Blotter, 1954 (Box 42)
    Hillbilly style cartoon on upper portion. Company product information and location information on lower half of page. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-063. Acme Plumbing Supply Company. Blotter, 1956 (Box 42)
    Hillbilly style cartoon on upper portion. Company product information and location on lower half of page. Color. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-064. Acme Plumbing Supply Company. Blotter, 1956 (Box 42)
  - 100-15-065. Acme Tool and Machinery. Pin-up poster, undated (Box 42)
    Titter Tatter proverbs. Warning: out of bounds. Item unfolds into poster of topless women. Some color. Mainly black-and-white Detaching along creases. Yellowing and dirt marks. Tears. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-066. Acme Storage and Furniture Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Acme. Any Thing. Any Time. Any Place. Black-and-white image and text. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-067. Acme Paper Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Action! Blotter Advertising to be effective should have attention value--select your illustration with care. Color image of sea birds. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-068. Hinde and Hinde Paper Company. Acme Bolster Roll postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Made of corrugated jute board. Never loses its shape. Weighs only 4 pounds. Sent express paid for $2.00. Image of woman holding up bolster roll with one hand. Black-and-white image and text. Company Info. Card unused. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-15-069. Acme Rendering Company. Card, 1940s (Box 42)
    Announcing a new public service. We will pay you for dead stock. Company information and contact information. Stamped, addressee: Rural Box holder, franked. Pen and pencil scribbles. Good condition.
  - 100-15-070. Acme Petroleum Company. Blotter, 1934 (Box 42)
    The Acme of Engineering Achievement. Black-and-white image and text. Company. Info. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-071. Acme Sextette Postcard, undated (Box 42)
    Black-and-white photograph of sextette. Unused. No information provided. Good condition.
  - 100-15-072. Acme forms Company. Blotter, 1946 (Box 42)
    Our forms will please you. Color. Image of semi-clad young woman to right. Dated. Some damage. Unused. Good condition.
  - 100-15-073. Acme Tent and Awning Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    Blue and white image and text. Company information and contact information. Some creases and marking. Good condition.
  - 100-15-074. Kalamazoo Cart Company. Card, 1886 (Box 42)
    Two Passenger Cart. The Acme Road, Breaking and Speeding Cart. Color lithographed image. Text on reverse is clear. Creases. Some water damage. Yellowing. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-075. Kalamazoo Cart Company. Card, 1886 (Box 42)
    The Acme Cart. Pat. Feb. 22 1886. The Acme Road, Breaking and Speeding Cart. Color lithographed image. Text on reverse is clear. Creases. Some water damage. Yellowing. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-076. C. Meyer Jr. Acme Fertilizer card, undated (Box 42)
    Color image of boy blowing horn on front. Company Information and advertising on reverse. Has been cut out of larger page. Torn on right side. Creases and yellowing. Fair condition.
  - 100-15-077. Acme Wagon Company. Card, undated (Box 42)
    Color image of farm animals in field. Acme Wagon Company. Farm Wagons and Carts. Good condition.
  - 100-15-078. Acme Oil Company. Card, 1880s (Box 42)
    Mica Axel Grease is the Best. Black-and-white image and text. One of series of produced cards sent on receipt of a 2c stamp. Company information and product description provided. Tape on reverse. Small tears and creases. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-079. Acme Oil Company. Card, 1880s (Box 42)
    Eldorado Caster. The Farmers Favorite. Black-and-white image and text. One of series of produced cards sent on receipt of a 2c stamp. Company information and product description provided. Small tears and creases. Fragile condition.
  - 100-15-080. Acme Oil Company. Card, 1880s (Box 42)
    Mica Axel Grease is the Best. Black-and-white image and text. Company information and product description provided. Good condition.
  - 100-15-081. Acme Oil Company. Card, 1880s (Box 42)
    American Coach Oil is Best. Lubricant for carriages, cabs, buggies, sulkies. Black-and-white image and text. Company information and product testimonials provided. Good condition.
  - 100-15-082. Atlantic Refining Company. Crown Acme Oil advertising, undated (Box 42)
    Crown Acme Oil. Best Illuminating Oil Made. Black-and-white text. Framed with color border. Taped to frame. Good condition.
  - 100-15-083. Acme Petroleum Co. One-month calendar, 1920 (Box 42)
    Color image of Suzanne. Let this portrait be a reminder to telephone, wire, write our nearest office when in the market for the following fuel oil, naphtha, kerosene. Good condition.
  - 100-15-084. Acme Garage. Calendar, 1926 (Box 42)
    Let George Do It. Color. Small calendar stapled to card. Good condition.
  - 100-15-085. Acme card, undated (Box 42)
    Zoology students Dissecting set--$2.00, Hand lens--$1.20. Red and white text. Store advertisement; incomplete address: 421 !4 Ave SE. Good condition.
  - 100-15-086. Geo D. Pohl, MFG Company. Acme Rapid Fire Dry Batteries card, undated (Box 42)
    Get Underway and get There With Acme Rapid Dry Batteries. Company information provided. Red and black text and images. Good condition.
  - 100-15-087. Acme- Evans Company. Blotter, undated (Box 42)
    White Plume Flour. Over A Century of Milling Progress. Color. Some ink on blotter. Good condition.